Finally found it!
Let's go.
Walk.
Stop right there.
Wait—there's someone here?
Did you all miss him?
Put the deed down—
and I'll let you go.
I will not.
I'll just walk right out of here.
Try and stop me.
You bunch of villains!
Put it down now!
You lot—
what a curious bunch you all are.
Think you can all just die?
If you want to leave—
you'll have to ask this broom of mine
if it agrees.
Get over here!
You old man!
Run? I'll chase!
Wait—
Now I've got you!
Are you all right?
Not exactly.
You dare hit me?
Old man, I'll hit you again.
I'll teach you to cause trouble!
Watch out—brawling!
Find somewhere to hide!
You old fool!
I'll teach you!
Changyu!
Changyu! Changyu, quick!
Aunt Zhuang!
Watch Ning'er for me.
Go!
Get out!
Miss Fan!
Listen to me—
I see who dares interfere!
Run! Run!
Changyu!
Stop! Stop fighting!
Old Zhao has half killed them.
If you hit them again, someone will die.
Still haven't learned?
Miss Fan!
Don't misunderstand.
We came this time
to congratulate you on your wedding.
That's right—congratulations!
We came to offer our blessings.
We never came for the deed.
Coming with weapons to offer blessings?
My husband is already injured,
and you attacked him on top of that.
No no—we didn't!
We never touched him!
Not a hair on him!
He scared himself.
He got scared—that's all.
We didn't touch him.
Getting scared doesn't count?
This must be the esteemed groom!
We failed to recognize a man of your stature.
Here, take some money—
some money for you.
We really did come to congratulate you.
Please spare us.
Get out of here.
Now.
Go! Run!
Well done! Well done! Well done!
Are you all right?
They did hurt you.
Let me go deal with them.
Don't blame them.
Then who?
Blame me.
I was sitting nearby.
It's partly my fault.
It's on me.
All right then—
watch your step! Careful!
Clumsy old man.
I only went out to buy vegetables,
and look at the state of things.
Thanks to Uncle for stepping in.
I can't thank you enough.
Aunt Zhao, you go rest.
Let me look after Yan Zheng.
All right.
I'll cook something for everyone.
Go, go, go!
Go on out.
Yan Zheng, give me your hand.
Old Zhao—come out here.
What is it?
What do you mean? Come here.
I haven't taken his pulse yet.
What pulse?
No sense of the moment.
No sense of the moment?
The wound on his back has torn open.
A large bloodstain.
I need to clean it.
I can do it myself.
Let me.
You caused this—it's only fair.
These wounds—
even from being sat on,
they shouldn't have torn this badly.
You must have been fighting.
Your build—
I can tell you know martial arts.
I was an escort guard.
Traveling the roads,
I learned some moves for protection.
I wasn't trying to hide it.
I understand.
My father was also an escort guard.
He had scars just like yours.
Escort work—
truly a life gambled with one's own body.
Hold still.
He was attacked by bandits
at Tiger's Fork Pass.
That's why he was hurt.
I see.
There's nothing valuable in the house.
They could have taken what they wanted.
So why did you fight back?
I would not let them take this.
You fought for the deed?
Thank you.
That one swing of my broom—
everyone went down.
I'm telling you—
back a cornered rabbit against a wall
and it'll bite.
If not for this fight,
I'd never have known I had it in me.
Ha! Indeed.
We're the warriors of West Lane.
That we are.
Have a drink!
Drink!
We're no worse than Marquis Wu'an!
Right?
Mind you,
you're looking a bit weak.
Let Old Zhao sit on you and down you go.
Changyu had better fatten you up.
His old wounds haven't healed.
Come on—have a drink with me!
Drink!
You can't drink with that wound.
He can drink—it helps blood flow.
Old Zhao!
Stop stirring things up.
Fresh wound—no alcohol.
Just because you like to be different.
Go sit over there.
Old Zhao! Come have a drink!
Let's drink!
Changyu—Fan Da really filed that complaint?
He's that shameless?
Should we hire a lawyer?
A lawyer would cost a lot.
What then?
What about Song Yan?
He's the only scholar in West Lane.
A licentiate doesn't have to kneel before officials.
He could surely help Changyu.
Big sister won't go to bad people for help.
Ning'er is right.
Right. Let's not mention that ingrate.
Come on, drink!
Here's to our brothers!
Drink!
Here.
Let me help you.
Just these.
My mother's things.
They'll have to do.
I've written out the court procedure
and the relevant laws.
Memorize them.
You can get through the hearing.
You know how to write?
And you know the law?
I've traveled widely.
You pick things up.
What's wrong?
I used to think
Song Yan was the most capable man in the world.
But you're even better.
Not only do you know martial arts,
you can write too.
Unlike that man—
the one Aunt Zhao called herself hoarse trying to get
who wouldn't even come out to help.
Would you argue the case for me?
By Da Yin law,
only the head of household may appear in court.
I am not the head of household.
I cannot appear in court.
Then I'm the one being thrown in.
My turn.
Order in the court!
Who are you and what is this case?
State your business.
You're so imposing.
I respectfully address Your Honor—
I am the commoner Fan Changyu.
I bring this case about—
a house.
Are your parents living?
Both deceased.
According to Da Yin law,
when a household has no male heir,
the property passes to the nearest male kin.
If an elder brother dies, the younger inherits.
If the younger dies—
Talking nonsense in my court!
Ning'er!
Silence!
The board!
You're serious?
I most respectfully address Your Honor.
According to Da Yin law,
Household Code, the Childless Household Article,
Number Seventeen—
the right to establish a successor—
Stop.
The right to establish a successor—
what does this mean?
Your Honor, I have trouble remembering written words,
so my mother taught me a rhyme
to help me remember.
I'm used to saying it that way—
I just can't help it.
Well then—
how about we find a sack
and tie Fan Da up?
Then what?
Uncle Wang said
if Fan Da isn't present at the hearing,
the case is void.
So once won't be enough.
There'll always be a next time.
Better to just—
kill him.
Get it over with.
Killing is against the law.
Better not.
If you can't be that ruthless,
then you'll just have to endure.
Keep memorizing.
[Advertisement]
Da Yin law, Household Code—
Da Yin law, Household Code,
Article Seventeen—
For a household without heirs,
stop being angry.
Your health matters.
I'll keep memorizing.
Fine.
Try memorizing the Seven-Step Poem instead.
The law ultimately comes down to reason.
An appeal to emotion might move the magistrate.
Magistrate Cui was a two-time examination graduate, after all.
What is the Seven-Step Poem?
Boiling beans over burning beanstalk;
the beans weep in the cauldron.
Born of the same root—
why burn me so fiercely?
What does it mean?
Burning the beanstalk to cook the beans—
describing brothers in a deadly struggle.
A metaphor for Fan Da bullying his brother's daughter,
cruel and without feeling.
Brilliant!
It's as if this poem was written for Fan Da.
Though he's not worthy of it.
What does 'cauldron' mean?
Same root—is that about having the same father?
And 'why burn me fiercely'—
is that a cooking method?
It's a metaphor for killing.
I've got it!
Burning beans on blazing stalks—
the beans
holler from the pot.
Same father gave us both life—
why am I killed first?
That's not quite right—
but not entirely wrong either.
Your Honor!
Burning beans on blazing stalks—
the beans holler from the pot.
Same father gave us both life—
why am I killed first?
Burning beans on blazing stalks—
the beans holler from the pot.
Same father gave us both life—
why am I killed first?
Your Honor!
Where is young Song going?
Son is just taking a stroll, mother.
He's been reading too long.
You still have the provincial exam,
and then the palace exam.
Don't get distracted.
Yes.
Boiling beans...
Mother.
I'm so tired.
Did I disturb you?
I just fell asleep with my head on your hand.
I understand—you're tired from reading too.
I completely understand.
Why is the lamp out?
I'll find a tinderbox.
Who knocks at this hour?
Song Yan.
Why have you come?
Let me in first.
Don't let my mother see.
I have something—
Something for you.
Changyu,
I came here at great risk—
defying my mother's express wishes—
to help you keep this home.
What?
These past days,
I've been thinking hard.
I finally found a solution.
I am here to tell you—
I am willing to take you as a concubine.
Have you been kicked in the head by a donkey?
Don't get excited—
I can only try to ask the magistrate
for a special exception.
But with my licentiate status,
he may grant me a favor.
That way you keep your home
and gain a proper status.
Song Yan.
You think that I—a pig butcher—
should be grateful
that you'd lower yourself to take me as a concubine?
I never meant it that way.
I simply didn't expect you
to be so rash about this house—
to give yourself to a crippled drifter from Chongzhou.
A crippled drifter.
Is that so.
So.
Song Yan, I'm genuinely curious—
what gives you the right to look down on him?
Never mind that Yan Zheng is accomplished and learned,
well-read and well-mannered—
in looks alone,
he outranks you ten to one.
More importantly,
he's grateful.
He understands my difficulties.
He agreed to marry into my household.
When I was in danger,
even with his own injuries,
he stood up for me.
That kind of loyalty and devotion—
isn't that worth a thousand times what you offer?
You're just bitter right now.
You want to look good in front of the neighbors.
That's why you came here.
Song Yan,
you want it all, don't you?
Every good thing in the world.
That's not it.
I care for you sincerely.
I, Song Yan, take your hand tonight
and swear to Heaven—
I—
Who are you?
Who am I?
A crippled drifter.
I've been pining for you night and day,
yet you show so little virtue?
What are you to her, that she owes you virtue?
You two have no shame—
absolutely indecent!
Utterly disgraceful!
According to Da Yin law,
illicit relations are punishable by eighty lashes!
breaking into a private home at night is treated as theft!
Beat him to death—he'd deserve it!
You see?
This is my husband.
Fan Changyu's lawfully wedded man.
You two—
how shameful!
Carrying on like this—it's an outrage!
Absolutely disgraceful.
As if I would kiss him.
If I scared him off from being my live-in husband,
I'd be getting the worst end of this deal.
Damn that Song Yan.
Damn him!
Damn him, damn him, damn him!
What on earth is that woman thinking?
All this for a live-in husband?
Aunt, where's Uncle?
He went to town.
Uncle Zhao is back!
Aunt, I have to step out for a moment.
Changyu.
These two—
why do they keep avoiding each other?
Before the wedding, girls get nervous.
Even a tough girl like Changyu
gets shy.
Were you shy before you married me?
Shy?
I was in tears and couldn't find the right temple door.
Yan Zheng.
Yan Zheng, you're awake.
Changyu just went out.
I know.
I need to speak with you, Uncle.
As it happens, I was looking for you too.
Come here.
Come.
Careful.
This essay you wrote—
how much did it actually sell for?
Is twenty taels a lot?
Twenty taels and you're asking if it's a lot?
I thought the bookseller had gone mad.
Already at Lin'an's Four Seasons Bookshop.
What kind of writing was it?
I travel widely and have seen a lot.
I just wrote down what I observed.
I didn't expect
the bookseller to actually buy it.
That's practically printing money.
Write a few more—I'll sell them.
I imitate the styles of great scholars.
Too many and my imitation would show.
Not wise.
Right, right—shouldn't flaunt it.
But writing one now and then—
that's enough to last a year.
This little bit—enough for a year?
For a modest household,
managed carefully,
it'd last two or three years.
Seems I've not budgeted well enough.
Keep my essay selling a secret.
Don't tell anyone.
I understand.
This old man can keep his mouth shut.
Won't go spreading it around.
This silly girl—
she found herself a husband who can earn money.
She's finally got some good fortune ahead.
Changyu!
Aunt.
You took forever—come see who's here!
Come look who's waiting for you!
Auntie Chen is here!
Long Yu, dear.
Open it up.
Open it and see.
Mine!
But you said you were only making his.
Girls always come first.
I saved on the fabric
and borrowed a little from a neighbor.
So—
I made you one too.
Thank you.
Of course.
It's beautiful.
See—
so beautiful.
What is this?
Don't you like it?
I like it.
But with such beautiful embroidery—
who's going to see it?
It's not for you to see.
If your husband likes it, that's what matters.
But this is for him to wear.
Oh, you silly girl.
You wear this on your wedding night—for him to see.
Aunt!
All right, all right.
Boiling beans over burning beanstalk,
the beans weep quietly in the cauldron.
Both from the same root—
why burn me so fiercely?
Boiling beans over burning beanstalk,
the beans weep loudly in the cauldron.
Oops—
the beanstalk shouldn't be hiding under the bed.
the beans weep loudly in the cauldron.
Both from the same root—
why burn me so fiercely?
Why are you here?
Didn't you say yesterday to come try on the wedding clothes?
But our wedding clothes
are at Aunt Zhao's place.
How did she end up sitting on the bed?
How did he end up sitting next to me?
Let's go try them on together.
Sure!
Let's go together.
Let's go.
Why isn't he leaving?
He couldn't have seen it—
Where's the box? I can't find it.
Have you finished memorizing? Done with your task?
Memorizing—
I—
Where was I?
Both from the same father...
Born of the same root...
I'll go first.
She probably hasn't seen it.
I'll give it to her another day.
Probably didn't see it.
Definitely didn't see. Definitely not.
How mortifying.
What do I do?
What a lively scene!
Son, you're here for Changyu's happy wedding day.
Make sure you remember all the steps.
Don't worry—you know best.
But today you're the host.
You just enjoy your tea. I'll handle it.
I heard the live-in husband is quite ugly?
A cripple too?
Neither ugly nor crippled—
who'd be a live-in husband these days?
Matchmaker Kang—on such a happy day,
watch your mouth.
She really talks too much.
Why is she here too?
A distant Fan family relative—can't be helped.
The groom leaving his family home—
what did I say?
See—not missing a single limb.
Who'd be a live-in husband these days?
I, Song Yan, late graduate, come to offer congratulations.
Why are you here again?
Ayu.
I'm giving you one last chance.
If you consent to be my concubine,
I'll honor my original vow and take you in.
A concubine!
Is he not disgusting?
He's deliberately humiliating my big sister.
He's here to humiliate my big sister?
This jade figurine is a love token Ayu once gave me.
Now that we are only as siblings,
I should pass it to her husband.
I gave you that clay doll when I was six.
How is that a love token?
You still remember something from when you were six—
clearly you never got over it.
Don't make me slap you.
A groom receiving a gift—how rude not to accept.
Live-in husband of the Fan family—
will you accept or not?
That face—
no wonder Changyu says she hasn't lost anything.
Who was the blind person who earlier said
the groom was some kind of ugly scarecrow?
Who was that?
That'd be you, Matchmaker Kang.
In all my years of matchmaking,
that face—never mind Song Yan being outclassed—
there's no one like that in all of Lin'an.
Not in the whole county.
I'm asking you—accept or not?
I—
accept.
Not accept—marry!
I meant accept the gift token—
not for them to get married!
Being too kind doesn't pay.
You raised that ungrateful creature.
Do you have anything else that might bite back?
I've raised many animals.
The only one that ever bit was that one.
Thank you.
Gold in your eyes—can't see jade.
Fan Changyu.
I'll forgive you for being blinded.
I'll ask you one final time:
do you or do you not—
You—
get out.
Fine.
Listen carefully.
One day, when I pass the palace exam,
you'll regret this.
You!
Fan Changyu! Yan Zheng!
Don't think you've won.
When I pass the highest exam,
you'll have something coming.
Bow to the elders!
Bow!
Sharing of the sacred meal—
henceforth in joy and sorrow together,
never to part.
Sharing of the wedding wine—
the three-cup ritual.
With respect and courtesy between spouses.
Joined cup ritual—
wine mingled as one.
May husband and wife be forever united.
Well done!
The couple bows to each other!
The wedding is complete!
Well done!
By tradition, a live-in husband takes the wife's surname.
No need.
My husband keeps his own name.
Yan Zheng.
That suits him just fine.
As for the children—
they should take the wife's family name.
Not necessary.
We'll have several—
some can take each surname.
Continue reading!
The most important part—
the live-in husband shall remember: the wife holds authority.
The woman is head of the household.
The husband answers to the wife in all things.
No need.
No, no need for all of that.
From this day forth,
the husband shall heed the wife in all matters.
And comply without exception.
In the future,
we shall discuss things together
and decide together.
Good.
Then what are we waiting for?
Escort the newlyweds to the bridal chamber!
Come, come!
Yan Zheng!
Let's go, Yan Zheng!
The bride is here to toast everyone!
Thank you, thank you, everyone!
Congratulations!
The new bride is toasting us!
Changyu, congratulations!
Everyone has worked so hard today.
Eat and drink your fill!
Toast the bride!
Come, come!
Everyone eat and drink well!
My girl.
Uncle Wang.
Forgive me.
I arrived late.
How could you only just arrive?
Uncle—
let me pour myself a penalty cup first.
Hurry, hurry!
These past days
have been hard on you.
I've seen it all.
I was your father's old friend.
From now on,
think of me as family.
Old Zhao over there counts as the other half.
My only wish for you
is that your days grow sweeter,
your paths grow wider,
your marriage harmonious,
your love enduring.
Good.
Thank you, Uncle Wang.
A toast!
Thank you all today.
Don't mention it.
She looks so beautiful.
You've worked hard today, Changyu.
Go rest.
Good.
Be careful on your way.
Congratulations, Changyu.
Beautiful—get some rest.
Sleep well.
What do you think you're doing?
I'm washing the bowls.
Wait—
you don't need to do that.
I don't need to?
He doesn't need to—with those injuries.
There'll be plenty of use for him later.
Hurry back to the bridal chamber!
Let me finish washing first.
You leave the washing!
Changyu! Don't just stand there!
Changyu! Changyu!
Go up to your room.
A wedding night is worth a thousand gold.
All right, all right!
Go, go, go.
Wait.
Forgive me.
I've lived alone for so long—
I keep forgetting there's a man in the house now.