There's no need.
He doesn't need to—with those injuries.
There'll be plenty of use for him later.
Hurry back to the bridal chamber!
Go, go!
Wait.
Forgive me.
I've lived alone so long—
I keep forgetting there's a man in the house.
Come in.
Let me help you.
No need.
I can do it myself.
Do what yourself?
You're really something.
Is it so hard to let someone help apply medicine?
With these wounds flaring up again and again—
how much silver does it take to treat,
how much suffering?
Men and women should not touch freely.
What do you mean, 'too close'?
When Song Yan came picking a fight,
didn't we already...?
That was not the same kind of touching.
Then carrying you back from the snow—
does that count?
I suppose.
Then that's fine.
Don't worry.
I have no improper intentions toward you.
With all these wounds,
even if I did, it wouldn't matter.
Fan Changyu—
listen to yourself.
This medicine—
no need to use too much.
Too much—
I use this much for Uncle Zhao.
You changed the dressing?
I didn't know.
Never mind.
Just bandage it for me.
These wounds—
all from escort work.
When I helped you change clothes earlier, I didn't notice.
It's fine.
I didn't want you to see—afraid you'd be alarmed.
Bear with me.
I'll wrap it up soon.
Other guards rely on skill.
You rely on sheer tenacity.
Don't be so reckless in the future.
At worst,
I'll work harder—
slaughter a few more pigs to keep you fed.
I'll go sleep downstairs with Ning'er.
No need.
I'll sleep
in the main hall downstairs.
That works too.
Let me bring you a basin of water.
You can clean yourself up.
I'll take your wedding robe downstairs.
Why are you hiding something like this?
That's not mine—
I thought you were resting your injuries.
I had no idea.
I'll let it go this time.
I'll throw this filth away for you.
No more looking at this.
So embarrassing.
What is it?
Come back, come back!
Be careful—someone might see.
She's coming down, she's coming down.
See?
I was right.
On their wedding night and they sleep apart.
This girl's marriage must be a sham.
Wife—
you're so clever.
That wretched girl
just wants to deceive the government
and hold onto the house by herself.
Look more closely inside.
I am looking closely.
I told you to look inside.
Who told you to look at that?
Go look over there.
Wife, something's off—
she just took in water and went back to the room.
This doesn't look like separate bedrooms.
Don't panic—let's watch a while longer.
What is it?
My uncle and aunt are eavesdropping outside.
They probably suspect
the marriage is a sham.
Come over here.
Can I stay here for a bit
and slip upstairs later?
Sleep here tonight.
If you leave,
outsiders will become suspicious.
Go close the windows.
What do you mean?
All the windows are shut.
Impossible—
in just that short a time,
that wretched girl managed to spot them.
A live-in husband who actually responds to her—
something must be off.
Hand me the candle.
Come sit over here.
Turn around.
Closer.
Oh—they're going to the bridal chamber!
Right here in the main hall?
Going to the bridal chamber!
Your clothes are soaked through with sweat.
Would you like to change?
Take off my outer robe.
Help me lie down.
Don't move.
Wife—look!
This is exactly like the book described.
Still watching?
That shameless girl—
blow out the candle.
Wife, the lamp is out.
Nothing to see.
Let's go.
Wait—
I still feel
something isn't right.
Where are you going?
I'll climb back over and look more carefully.
Look carefully!
Damn wild cat—
stealing my meat again!
That's no cat.
Who's out there?
Indeed—such an animal.
How shameless.
Stealing meat in the middle of the night.
Next time I catch you,
I won't let you off.
Is that girl really consummating the marriage?
Let's hurry and leave—
or we'll be the ones who get buried here.
Quick, quick!
Thank you.
[Advertisement]
Just this one piece?
This piece, this piece—
look!
Full weight and measure!
More please!
Sure!
Buying braised meat!
This—
pig ear.
One jin.
Thank you!
Just the right fat-to-lean ratio?
Perfect.
Thank you, shopkeeper.
Shopkeeper, buying meat!
Coming!
Two jin, how's that?
That works.
Good work.
Sold out already.
Yin Niang.
Ayu.
Just got married and you're already open for business?
Shouldn't you rest at home?
I want to earn more money—
get my parents' pig pens back up and running soon.
Naturally I need to work harder.
Besides, there's another mouth to feed at home.
Yes, got to work harder.
How did your live-in husband
perform last night?
Fine—can eat and sleep.
His wounds are much better.
That's not what I'm asking.
Making children is serious business.
Your live-in husband looks tall and strong.
He must be quite capable.
What are you saying?
Listen to yourself—
I don't understand a word.
What do you mean you don't understand? Come along.
What's this about?
They're rounding up drifters from Chongzhou again.
Yin Niang, watch the shop for me.
I'll be right back.
Where are you going?
All handled.
Put it away now.
Thank you, Uncle Wang.
Come over here.
What is it?
Here's some silver for your trouble.
There's no need for silver.
You two are legally married.
Everything was done properly.
Don't treat me as an outsider.
Then thank you, Uncle Wang.
Of course.
All right.
It's cold—go on home.
Sold! Sold! Sold!
Sold already!
How could you sell it?
I had a redeemable pawn ticket.
Look at the ticket more carefully.
It was redeemable, yes,
but there's a clause—
unclaimed after ten days becomes a permanent sale.
Look here—
that's your signature.
Those characters are so tiny no one could read them.
Even if I could see them, I can't read.
Miss Fan,
I can't very well teach you to read
while you pawn things here.
You cheated me.
We followed the contract.
I truly don't understand—
a rough silver hairpin—
that gentleman wanted it too.
You want to redeem it?
What's so special about it?
What gentleman?
Where did he go?
Home.
A customer's information—
speak.
That was the only memento
my parents left me.
He was a young man—
I truly don't know who he is.
How much did you sell it for?
Just twenty taels.
How could you sell it just because someone offered more?
We have the ticket as proof.
We have the pawn ticket.
Even if you took this to the county court,
I'm not afraid.
Changyu, what are you doing here?
What happened? What's wrong?
Changyu.
All the candy I'd been hiding was eaten by ants.
Don't cry.
Didn't Father find a way for you?
See—
now the ants can't get it.
Father is the best!
Can you
hide this candy for me?
You clever little thing.
I knew you had more candy hidden.
Don't tell your mother, all right?
Or she'll scold us both.
Yes, Father.
Go pluck some grass for Father.
Father gives—
this way,
you won't lose it.
Father is the best!
You—
remember:
every hardship can be overcome.
Let the tears fall,
but keep walking the road.
When the sky falls, a tall person holds it up.
We always eat well and sleep soundly.
Yes, Father.
Good girl.
Thank you, thank you.
See you next time.
Walk carefully.
Carefully, carefully.
Song family's little sister,
so you're moving to the grand mansion in town.
What good fortune!
With the magistrate's favor,
our Scholar Song has done well for himself.
Hoping that next year
he passes all three imperial exams
and brings honor to our town.
He'll surely pass.
Thank you for the kind words.
Little sister,
now that your Song Yan is about to become
the magistrate's son-in-law,
can you make good on your promise—
get my grandson relieved of his labor duty
and get him a constable post?
As for Fan Changyu being a jinx—
I've already spread that around the whole village.
Absurd.
When did I ever ask you to spread that?
No, no—nothing. Nothing.
Nothing at all.
Don't worry.
When the time comes,
I'll have Scholar Song speak to the magistrate.
Understood, understood.
Fan girl—stop right there.
Stand still!
Every hardship can be overcome.
When the sky falls, a tall person holds it up.
We may not meet again as neighbors.
This is our small token of good will.
We hope you'll accept it.
And please return our betrothal letter.
Right—
you've already gotten married now.
Why are you still holding onto their betrothal letter?
This little bit of money—
how much do we owe your family?
And when was this—who saw it?
Who even saw it?
Right—
no proof, no one will believe it.
If the Song family really borrowed money from you,
why would they borrow one year and not repay the next?
Who gives for over a decade
without expecting anything in return?
It would practically make them living Buddhas.
Fine, fine.
Here's all this money.
Is that enough?
Return our betrothal letter.
Everyone take a look—
this much money isn't enough?
You, Fan girl,
are truly insatiably greedy.
Clouded by greed.
Move aside!
Out of the way!
Bad people picking on big sister!
Brother-in-law stands up for big sister!
Who's this?
That's Changyu's husband.
Him?
He's still a cripple—
your wounds haven't healed yet.
You shouldn't be out like this.
It's fine.
Even injured,
nothing stops me from coming to bring you home.
What business is the Fan family's affair of yours—a live-in husband?
I now carry the Fan name too.
Want the debt repaid?
Fine.
Let's first settle what the Song family owes the Fan family,
then you can move at your leisure.
One coffin: six taels, twenty coins.
Twelve feet of fine cloth: one tael, ten coins.
Thirty baskets of eggs: one tael, fifty coins.
Three years of school fees: nine taels, sixty coins.
Song Yan, that poor scholar,
truly relied on the Fan family's support
to get an education.
And yet—
no sooner did Song Yan pass the provincial exam
than Fan Changyu's parents were barely cold in their graves
before he forced her to break off the engagement.
And the Song family's clothing, food, and daily expenses—
all funded by the Fan household.
Where's his shame?
Exactly.
And what did Uncle record as expenses?
Three years of school fees for that ungrateful wretch—
one year alone is three taels, twenty coins.
Calculate three years—
nine taels, sixty coins.
That's not a small amount.
Plus pork at every festival—
at least twenty portions or more.
That adds up to over two taels.
And two years ago, when Song Yan fell ill,
just the medicine alone cost over one tael.
Fan Er paid for all of it.
He didn't dare let Fan Er's wife
or Changyu know.
The more I talk, the angrier I get.
Even the woman's monthly goods—
four bamboo baskets, thirty bundles of firewood,
five buckets of lamp oil,
three copper basins,
bamboo sleeping mats,
and—
Ning'er, come back.
Don't fall in the ditch.
—and four bundles of monthly cloths.
Monthly cloths?
They borrowed monthly cloths?
And last year at the Dragon Boat Festival,
Old Madam Song came to visit
and stole a braised pig tail while leaving.
Adding it all up,
the Fan family
practically supported the entire Song household.
Matchmaker Kang, speaking up for the Songs—
how big was your cut?
Don't talk nonsense—
I got nothing.
I'm the same as everyone here—
I was just passing by.
I really was just passing by—
I got nothing.
You—a grown man—
talking about women's intimate items.
You're a disgrace to scholars.
Monthly cloths are natural—the very source of motherhood.
What is there to be ashamed of?
You may be ashamed to say it,
but you certainly asked for it often enough—
one bundle at a time,
every other two weeks.
You should see a doctor.
Go see a doctor.
What's it to you?
What are you laughing at?
What's so funny?
What's it to all of you?
Neighbors, please don't say hurtful things.
You're all underestimating the genuine kindness
that Uncle and Aunt Fan showed to me.
They are gone now.
We should not speak ill of the dead.
Ayu,
though you always speak harshly to me,
I don't hold it against you.
I also know your rushed marriage
has something to do with me.
Even so,
from here on we go our separate ways.
But if you ever fall on hard times,
send word to my household.
I will always be your Song Yan.
I—
spare me your kind words.
If not for my sake,
would your mother have treated you so well?
I blame myself for being blind.
What rotten luck—
I fell for a literate, ungrateful wolf.
Pay back the money.
Right, pay it back.
A gentleman parts ways without harsh words.
I'll pay you back.
Rounding off the small change—
thirty taels total.
Count it yourself if you don't believe me.
Give it to her.
We don't have that much money at home.
If you're short,
write a promissory note.
There's no brush and ink here.
When I move to town, I'll write one and send it.
Who needs brush and ink?
Bite your finger,
press your thumbprint.
Right, a thumbprint.
Quick.
Stop—
don't listen to them.
Wait, wait!
Just a few dozen taels—
I'll repay it for him.
Miss Cui—
how could we ask you to come down to a place like this?
Scholar Song is my father's student.
It's only right I help.
A student of the Son of Heaven—
how can he be schemed against
by someone reeking of money?
Some people are born noble.
Like me—
my father named me Qianjin,
meaning a thousand gold,
destined never to lack for silver.
Born to command others.
And some are born lowly.
Like you—
orphaned from childhood,
with no one in this world.
This jade may be beautiful,
but it's worth less than gold and silver.
Here's fifty taels.
Pick it up.
All right, Chang Ning—
we don't take what isn't ours.
The betrothal letter has long been placed
under the stone at your door.
Mother—
we've been over for a long time.
This extra money is just interest.
After all,
your pride
isn't worth much.
What isn't mine, I won't take.
Besides—
he isn't worth it.
Wait—I'm not done speaking.
Come back here.
So rude. Scholar Song,
come help me.
Whoever picks up those coins can keep them.
This money belongs to whoever wants it.
Sure, sure—come, come.
Finally—
finally found it.
Tear it up.
Ning'er, come home with your brother-in-law.
He's just a provincial licentiate.
In Da Yin, with seventeen prefectures—
how many licentiates are there each year?
Who does Song Yan think he is?
In the future,
just say this kind of thing to me,
not in front of outsiders.
People will laugh.
Laugh?
Laugh at what?
They'll laugh at you—
for not even having a licentiate's degree.
I know you're saying this to cheer me up.
Why would I cheer you up?
Never mind a licentiate—
even a palace exam graduate
is nothing special.
You really think highly of yourself.
I—
I see you're smart,
your handwriting is good.
Why not study and take the exams?
If you pass the provincial exam,
you'd get an official post.
My ambitions don't lie in officialdom.
What a pity.
I was counting on you becoming a great official
and finding ways to give that Song fellow trouble.
Fine.
What's wrong?
Actually, what makes me sad
isn't Song Yan.
It's my mother's hairpin—I can't get it back.
The truth is, that hairpin—I let my parents down.
I pawned it as a redeemable pawn,
but ran into a dishonest pawnbroker
who sold it to some fool.
That fool
paid twenty taels for it.
Twenty taels.
So much money—
I could never afford that.
Tell me—how can there be someone in the world
who just creates problems for others?
How did this end up with you?
That gentleman—
are you the one who paid twenty taels to redeem it?
You could say that.
You're back.
Wait.
That dishonest pawnbroker cheated you out of twenty taels.
I need to get that money back.
Actually, that gentleman
is the bookshop owner.
He paid twenty taels for the hairpin.
He appreciates my essays,
so when he sent payment for my writing,
he included the hairpin as a bonus.
What a coincidence.
Yes.
Here's the silver.
You sell essays
and earn this much?
Uncle Zhao can vouch for that.
Where is that bookshop?
I want to return the money to the gentleman.
No need.
That gentleman has great wealth.
He doesn't miss twenty taels.
Still, I should thank him.
Of course.
Once my wounds heal,
I'll take you to visit.
All right.
Actually,
you don't need to sell essays to support the household.
I said—
I can raise pigs and keep you.
Mother.
I found the hairpin.
Before,
I was always afraid of doing the wrong thing,
afraid you wouldn't approve of my choices,
afraid you'd be angry.
Now this hairpin
has come back to me by a winding path.
It must be you watching over us from above.
I'm at ease now.
Let me help you.
Wait.
Brother An,
I have a chicken leg.
Want some?
I—
I don't eat chicken legs.
I have a big one here.
Look.
This is most improper.
How can one eat meat in such a refined place of learning?
Aren't you afraid the headmaster will scold you?
You clumsy bird—
you always lose your way coming here.
I know, I know.
Wait here a moment.
Your punishment copy is considered complete.
The rest of you may go.
Thank you, Headmaster.
Brother An, thank Headmaster Gongsun.
Thank you, Headmaster Gongsun.
I am currently staying at the Fan family home in Lin'an
to recover from my injuries.
Here are my household papers and travel documents for verification.
Well, you, Xie Jiuheng—
I knew a fellow like you wouldn't die so easily.