Miss Fan.
I agree.
Drink it while it's hot.
What I mean is—
about the live-in marriage,
I agree.
Good.
After we are properly wed,
I'll tell everyone you married into my family.
Once the house is transferred to my name
and the finances are settled,
I'll find you the very best doctor in town,
the best medicine to treat your wounds.
Once you've healed,
you may stay or go—
whatever you wish.
Aren't you worried that once I leave,
your uncle will come back to seize the house?
Once the house is officially transferred,
what have I to fear from him?
When you do leave,
I'll just say you went away on business.
Who would know the difference?
You've thought this through.
If you stay,
I'll raise pigs and provide for you.
Why?
You may not know,
but we pig butchers earn quite a good living.
What I mean is—
if I became a burden,
what would you get out of keeping me?
I get to look at a handsome face.
Fan Changyu!
How can you say
something so honest?
There are so many
handsome people in this world.
I know, but—
you're the one I carried out of the snow.
If you have nowhere to go after healing,
once healed,
I will take my leave.
I won't impose any further.
That's fine.
I'll head off then.
Miss Fan.
For saving my life,
I will repay you one day.
Is there anything you wish for?
Feel free to say.
There's nothing else I need.
You're willing to pretend to marry into my family
and help me keep the house—
that alone makes me grateful.
Pretending to be a live-in husband
is repayment enough for taking me in.
Is there a wish
you want to dream bigger?
A wish?
Dream bigger?
Then I'll think big.
I want to get my father's pig pens
up and running again.
Fence off a bigger plot of land,
raise twenty or thirty pigs.
Think even bigger—
a hundred pigs.
What I mean is—
do you have any grand life ambitions?
A hundred pigs would be worth over a hundred taels.
That's not a grand life ambition?
Then two hundred.
I wouldn't be able to slaughter them all.
I understand.
Let's seal it with a handshake.
Good day, Miss Changyu.
Good.
Changyu, big sister!
Go play.
Good.
Thank you, Miss.
You're welcome.
Mistress Wang.
Changyu.
Sister Wang, Sister Zhang.
Ladies.
My mother previously deposited fabric here
for me to have wedding clothes made.
Come this way.
Of course.
Yes, there is some fabric set aside—
just enough to make one wedding outfit.
Can it be made into a man's wedding robe?
A man's wedding robe?
I knew that voice sounded familiar!
Isn't this our little Changyu?
Auntie Chen!
I heard from Aunt Zhao
that you're getting married too.
When is the happy day?
Getting the wedding clothes made now—
won't that be rushing it a bit?
Ever since word got out about Chongzhou drafting soldiers,
everyone's rushing to marry,
wanting to leave an heir at home.
My helpers in the shop
can barely keep up.
I heard from Aunt Zhao
that the groom is quite handsome.
He's all right.
At least I'm not getting the short end.
Auntie Chen, please work quickly—
I'll pay you extra.
Don't even talk about extra pay!
Don't you worry.
I helped your mother choose and set this fabric aside.
She so wanted to see you wed.
I heard from Aunt Zhao
that the groom is her distant relative from Chongzhou.
From Chongzhou?
Does he know whether Marquis Wu'an really died?
Marquis Wu'an is dead.
Really?
Marquis Wu'an—
Haven't you heard what everyone's saying outside?
Marquis Wu'an is dead.
Died in Chongzhou.
Not even a bone left.
Just like his father.
Nonsense!
How could Marquis Wu'an die?
I'll smash that mouth of yours!
Everyone—should he be beaten?
We of Da Yin
have faced the Northern Di on the battlefield for many years.
Marquis Wu'an Xie Zheng—a hero of his generation—
has fallen without a body to bury.
This is a great sorrow for our nation.
We, Your Majesty,
wish to posthumously honor Xie Zheng as the Duke of Loyalty,
and award his army one thousand gold taels.
What does the court say?
Your Majesty is most wise.
Marquis Wu'an defended our western borders
with unmatched valor.
In over a hundred years of our dynasty,
this honor has been bestowed
on only one man—Xie Zheng.
To now confer upon him the title of Duke of Loyalty—
this truly reflects Your Majesty's virtue
and is a blessing for all people.
Marquis Wu'an rose to command armies at a young age
and avenged the humiliation at Jinzhou.
The Northern Di trembled at his name.
All soldiers will shed their blood
to repay Your Majesty's grace.
I second the motion.
Then let the imperial decree be issued.
We mourn deeply.
The court shall wear mourning attire.
The whole nation shall observe a period of mourning.
We obey Your Majesty's decree.
Your Majesty, I arrived late—
The Chancellor has been unwell
yet still comes to court.
This is a blessing for Da Yin.
Please be seated.
What have I missed?
We intend to honor Xie Zheng as the Duke of Loyalty,
award his army one thousand gold taels,
and order a national period of mourning.
What is the Chancellor's view?
Marquis Wu'an did earn great merit in battle,
but this concerns the situation at the front.
A national period of mourning
may affect the morale of our armies.
The Northern Di and Prince Changxin's forces
would seize this opportunity.
With respect, Chancellor—
Marquis Wu'an gave his life for his nation in his prime.
His Majesty honors his early death out of compassion.
This is a mark of imperial benevolence.
While scholars criticize his actions at Jinzhou,
his merits far outweigh his faults.
When merit and fault are weighed,
merit wins without question.
His Majesty rewarding Marquis Wu'an now
is a clear and just act,
a measure to inspire all soldiers.
How could it harm morale?
The Marquis's death has been reported,
yet no body has been found.
I chose not to report it publicly
to keep our enemies guessing.
As long as his death is not confirmed,
our enemies cannot be certain of our weakness
and will not dare strike recklessly.
The Grand Tutor is skilled at reading the Emperor's mind,
but in matters of military strategy,
there is still much to learn.
The Chancellor speaks with great wisdom.
I have much to learn.
Chancellor.
Please accept my condolences.
Thank you for your kind words, Grand Tutor.
Now that Marquis Wu'an no longer guards Yanzhou,
who will
command the Yanzhou army?
The Yanzhou army is still Da Yin's army.
Any capable man at court
may be sent to Yanzhou.
The Yanzhou army is vital to border security.
We must proceed with the utmost care.
If the Chancellor has a perfect plan,
then I am the one who worried for nothing.
I'll take my leave.
That old fox, so concerned about the northwest—
he must be plotting to gain control of the border forces.
Have Xie Zheng's remains been found?
Not yet.
Has the eldest son reported anything
about the Marquis's disappearance?
Nothing.
That day, they were too close to General He Jingyuan's territory.
Fearing to alarm our quarry,
I've dispatched men to continue searching in secret.
Search harder.
Tell them to be quick.
Whether he lives or dies must be confirmed.
But more importantly, find that keepsake.
Yes.
Tell the agents of the Xuan Division—
if they fail to find it,
don't bother coming back.
By your command.
Get out of the way!
Get lost!
Move!
Where did this wild wolf come from?
My hair ribbon nearly got snatched.
Where are my shoes?
This young lady truly isn't afraid of the cold—
out in the snow,
walking barefoot on the road.
She must have met with some misfortune.
Let's ask where she lives
and give her a ride.
Miss,
my master takes pity on you
walking in the snow.
He offers to take you home. Where do you live?
No need, thank you.
Miss, please wait.
My name is Li.
I mean no harm.
Walking barefoot in this weather—
your feet will be ruined.
Please allow me to take you.
Then thank you, sir.
Thank you, sir.
But you sitting outside—
I feel terrible about it.
Think nothing of it.
Your shoes and socks are soaked through.
Warm your feet first.
I've been sitting inside the carriage too long—
I needed some fresh air.
Sister, you're back so soon!
Changyu!
What happened to you?
A wild wolf chased me on the road.
I lost one shoe.
Thankfully these two gentlemen gave me a ride.
It was nothing.
Thank you both, sirs.
It's so cold out—
please come inside and warm up.
Aunt.
Let Miss Fan change her shoes first.
We have urgent matters
and must be on our way.
Thank you, Mr. Li.
Sorry to trouble you.
Please, gentlemen—wait.
I just finished roasting some chestnuts.
Take some for the road.
There's no need.
My aunt's roasted chestnuts are delicious.
They really are.
Take some and try.
Then we gratefully accept.
Thank you, kind Aunt.
Just a moment.
Aunt.
Why did you do that?
The country folk show gratitude
in simple, honest ways.
We need to blend in with the locals.
It helps with the investigation.
Right?
Just admit you wanted the chestnuts.
I saw nothing.
Come in.
I—I—
I went to Auntie Chen's today to get the wedding clothes made,
and I just realized I forgot to take your measurements.
Come in.
You look slender,
but your shoulders are quite broad.
Like my father.
Shoulder width: one foot eight.
Waist: two foot one.
Inseam: three foot seven.
What's wrong?
Nothing.
I was chased by a wolf this morning.
I may have twisted my ankle.
Sit down—let me take a look.
No need.
Uncle Zhao will be back soon.
I'll just put some medicine on it.
Sit down.
Let me check.
Don't let it hurt more tonight.
[Advertisement]
Is it good?
For some reason,
those mysterious men retreated after reaching Lin'an.
They vanished completely.
Perhaps
I should ask the local magistrate.
My mentor has instructed
that this matter be kept private.
My Lord,
you've been riding all night
searching for Marquis Wu'an
with no result.
I'd say
in the chaos of battle,
leaving no remains
is not uncommon.
I have a feeling
Marquis Wu'an didn't die so easily.
If those mysterious men still linger,
the Marquis must be in Lin'an.
It's dislocated.
Ow, ow, ow!
Of course it hurts—it was fully dislocated.
I thought it was just a sprain.
Bear with me.
Done.
My Lord,
freshly roasted chestnuts—
still hot.
Please, help yourself.
Thank you, Aunt.
Aunt,
just now I heard
Miss Fan calling from upstairs.
Is everything all right?
That's Changyu's live-in husband.
The young couple is probably just playing around.
A husband?
Why didn't we see him come downstairs to greet Miss Fan?
He has some injuries.
He can't easily come down.
Tasty?
Yes, yes, very tasty, Aunt.
Now the northwest is at war.
I hear many wounded drifters
from Chongzhou have come here,
trying to settle by getting married.
The Fan girl's husband—
he's not from Chongzhou too, is he?
He's a distant relative of mine.
He came from Yanzhou.
It really doesn't hurt anymore.
Not even a little.
Told you not to wolf it down.
Now you're paying for it.
Aunt,
may I trouble you for a cup of tea?
Of course, of course!
I was so busy getting you food,
I forgot about drinks.
Please come in for some tea.
Thank you.
Someone came downstairs?
Oh no!
I completely forgot about our two guests downstairs!
The tea isn't great—please forgive us.
Miss Fan, you just got married?
Actually,
he married into my household.
A live-in husband.
Poor soul.
Just arrived in Lin'an from Yanzhou,
and ran into bandits.
Robbed and wounded.
Fortunately my Changyu took him in.
Changyu even slaughtered a pig
and sold it to pay for his treatment.
Slaughtered a pig?
My big sister is amazing—
one slap and she can knock a pig out cold.
She's joking.
Miss Fan is most admirable.
Most admirable indeed.
Miss Fan, no need to see us out.
Take care.
Walk safely.
My Lord,
I think we're so obsessed with finding Marquis Wu'an
that we're imagining things.
Marquis Wu'an was someone who refused even a princess.
How could he possibly marry into a pig butcher's family
and even massage her foot to set her ankle?
I was overthinking it.
You've gone several nights without sleep over this.
Rest on the way back to Jizhou.
I'll handle things out here.
Let's go.
Carriages from Jizhou.
General He Jingyuan's men.
What measurements did I take for Yan Zheng?
Shoulder width—
one foot eight.
Waist—
two foot one.
Inseam—
three foot seven.
Yan Zheng.
What is this?
Could she have discovered something?
Who is it?
It's me.
I have something to say.
Come in.
I've already noted the measurements.
I'll send them to the tailor shortly.
Could you stay awake tonight?
Wait until I come back.
There's something I need us both to do.
Just the two of us?
You're a man; I'm a woman.
I can't do it without you.
That seems improper.
You're about to become my live-in husband.
What's improper about it?
It's settled. Not a word to Uncle and Aunt Zhao.
Keep it secret.
What do you need me to do?
Follow me—don't let anyone see.
Kneel down.
This is what you wanted
the two of us to do together?
My mother always said
paying respects at night requires a man
with strong yang energy.
That's you.
So that's why she was writing
in the dirt today.
The magistrate hasn't issued an official death notice.
Unofficial memorial rites could get us in trouble.
The middle of the night when no one's around is best.
Then whose memorial tablet is that?
When you were coughing blood badly,
I thought you might not make it.
So I carved one for you.
Thank you.
No need—it wasn't used after all.
Now that Marquis Wu'an has died in battle,
I wanted to give him a memorial tablet.
As luck would have it,
your name can be slightly changed to fit.
Yes.
Might as well put it to use.
It's made of huang hua li wood.
Might as well use it.
By the way—
you escaped from Chongzhou.
Do you know how the Marquis died?
I don't know.
You have no connection to him,
so why pay your respects?
Common gossip says
that Marquis Wu'an was a bloodthirsty demon
who slaughtered entire cities.
Nonsense.
My father said
in over two hundred years of Da Yin,
how many men like Marquis Wu'an were there?
He reclaimed Jinzhou.
Decades of fighting,
losing countless great generals.
The twelve commanderies of Liaodong—
he reclaimed those too.
Today's scholars all despise that.
Those so-called men of letters
call him cold and brutal.
But the soldiers and people who died at Jinzhou sixteen years ago—
were they not innocent?
General Xie stood tall and died with dignity,
yet the Northern Di disemboweled him
and displayed his body on the city wall.
He was the Marquis's own father.
Avenging one's father is only right.
Besides the Marquis,
who else could guard the northwest?
Why are you looking at me like that?
Did I say something wrong?
You're remarkably bold.
There's no one else here.
That's why I dare say it.
Marquis Wu'an,
I, the commoner Fan Changyu,
kneel here with my husband Yan Zheng
to bid you farewell.
May your spirit rest in peace.
May your blessings protect the people of Da Yin.
If you meet my parents in the afterlife,
please give them my regards.
Is there anything you wish to say?
Kneel and speak it.
Marquis Wu'an gave his life for his country.
He is worthy of this bow.
May the fog of deception lift.
May the truth
be revealed to the world.
Big sister.
Your braid is crooked.
Come here, let me see.
It doesn't look crooked.
Make do for today.
When I've sold the pork,
I'll buy you some candy.
Go get dressed.
Good morning, Changyu!
Morning, Changyu!
Good morning, Miss!
Morning!
Changyu!
Morning, Changyu!
Morning!
Morning, Changyu, dear!
Changyu, dear,
are you giving away the braised pig hearts today?
Not today.
The braised hearts are for sale.
I only gave them away on opening day.
From now on, they're sold.
Thirty coins per jin.
But other butchers include offal for free
when you buy meat.
Which shop?
Master Guo's—
buy meat, get free offal.
Come on over!
Are you doing the same?
If not, I'll go to his shop.
Of course I am!
Good, then I won't go.
Weigh me two jin of shoulder pork.
Here you are, Aunt Tao.
And here's your braised heart. Take it.
Right then.
Here you go, miss.
Your meat.
That Master Guo—
he stopped you from giving away extras,
then started doing it himself.
He has a cousin who clerks at the magistrate's office.
Watch out.
Understood.
Look at this meat.
Still better to buy from Fan's.
The lean cuts are a deeper red,
and the braised flavors are richer.
Not like over there—pale as dead pig meat.
What's that about?
I bet their braised sauce is made with real gold water.
Good thing you're back—
let's see how long that free offal routine lasts.
Talking about me, are you?
We'll see who lasts.
Yin Niang, my noodles?
So impatient!
You'd think I was starving you.
Coming right up.
I'm just hungry!
Hurry up.
Changyu—
I'll head off now.
If that Guo fellow gives you trouble again,
just tell me.
I'm not afraid of him.
See you!
How many jin?
Two jin will do.
Two jin it is—make it two for me as well.
Foolish bird.
Falling for such an obvious trap.
Come up.
Go on.
Already at Lin'an's Four Seasons Bookshop.
Hurry.
While that girl is away,
search quickly.
You two—check outside.
I'll go upstairs.
Back courtyard: clear.
Kitchen: empty.
Upstairs: nobody.
We shouldn't cause extra trouble now.
Besides, there's nothing valuable in here.
Listen—
if we don't find the deed this time,
we lose our jobs.
Search properly.
Fine.
Uncle Wang looks busy today.
I won't trouble you further.
About the property transfer—
Say no more.
Fan Da
has already filed his complaint.
The hearing will be within ten days.
Be ready.
One more thing—
on my wedding day,
please come early for the celebration.
Of course, my girl.
You're quick!
Congratulations in advance.
I'll definitely be there.
One more thing to ask of you.
My husband's money and travel papers
were taken by bandits.
He's about to register as my live-in husband.
Could I apply for replacement papers?
With all the crackdowns on drifters right now,
getting replacement papers
is not easy.
But your father once did me a great kindness.
I'll take care of this for you.
Thank you, Uncle Wang.
Fortunate to have you here.
Don't mention it.
Just consider it a wedding gift.
Look at this carefully.
Found it!
Come, look!
See—
that wretched girl.
Hid it behind the grain jars.
What a search.
Finally found it.
Stop right there.
Wait—there's someone in here?
How did you all miss him?
Put the deed down
What?
I said—
put the deed down
and I'll let you go.
A three-legged man
thinks he's tough?
A cripple—
can't even stand up straight,
and you want to fight?
Think I can't break that one good leg of yours?
Try me.
See—
that wretched girl,
hid it behind the grain jars.
What a search.
Finally found it.
Stop right there.
Wait—there's someone in here?
How did you all miss him?
Put the deed down—
What?
I said—
leave the deed,
and I'll let you go.
A three-legged man
thinks he's so tough?
A cripple—
you can barely even stand,
and you want to fight?
Think I can't break that one good leg of yours?
You're a cripple!
Try me.